

George Christodoulou

Stavridi 7, 45332 Ioannina, Greece Contact via email: g.christodoulou@uoi.gr

Contact via phone: +306973180106

Contact online: github.com/GiorgosChristodoulou linkedin.com/in/george-ch

SUMMARY

I received my diploma in Computer Science and Engineering from the Computer Science and Engineering Department of the University of Ioannina in 2017. I received my MSc in Computer Science with specialization in software from the Computer Science and Engineering Department of the University of Ioannina in 2020. My research interests include Data Management and Query processing (Efficient Data Indexing and Retrieval on temporal data). Currently, I am pursuing my PhD degree from the Computer Science and Engineering Department of the University of Ioannina.

EXPERIENCE

 Research Assistant at Centre for Research & Technology Hellas (CERTH) worked on designing and developing an Anomaly detector based on machine learning techniques for the 'Secure and Safe IoT' (SerIoT) project. Python, PyTorch, Tensorflow 	May 2019 – Sep 2019
 Software engineer Intern at Natech S.A., Ioannina, Greece worked on designing and developing a ASP.NET MVC web application C#, MVC 	Jul 2016 – Aug 2016
Networks lab assistant at University of Ioannina, Department of Computer Science & Engineering, Greece	Oct 2017 - Jan 2019
Java lab assistant at University of Ioannina , Department of Computer Science & Engineering , Greece	Mar 2018 - June 2018
Python lab assistant at University of Ioannina, Department of Computer Science & Engineering, Greece	Oct 2019 – Jan 2022

EDUCATION

University of Ioannina, Department of Computer Science & Engineering, Greece

Diploma in Computer Science & Engineering

Sep 2011 - Sep 2017

- \rightarrow Grade: 6.74
- → thesis: Routing Methods with Machine Learning on Delay Tolerant Networks.
 - Redesign and optimization of a routing protocol with machine learning techniques, C++

0

- MSc in Computer Science & Engineering
 - → Grade: 9.08

Oct 2017- Feb 2020

- → thesis: A Prefix-based Hybrid Solution for Main Memory Indexing
 - Development of Main memory Index with binary representations of data, C++
- Currently pursuing PhD in Computer Science & Engineering
 - \rightarrow Advisory Committee :

Mar 2020 - Present

- Prof. Nikolaos Mamoulis (Supervisor)
- Prof. Panagiotis Vasiliadis
- Prof. Panagiotis Tsaparas

PUBLICATIONS

George Christodoulou, Panagiotis Bouros and Nikos Mamoulis:

HINT: A Hierarchical Index for Intervals in Main Memory

Proceedings of the 2022 ACM International Conference on Management of Data (**ACM SIGMOD**), Philadelphia, PA, USA, June 12-17, 2022

George Christodoulou

Efficient and Scalable Management of Interval Data

International Conference on Extending Database Technology (EDBT' 23) PhD Workshop

George Christodoulou, Panagiotis Bouros and Nikos Mamoulis:

HINT: A Hierarchical Interval Index for Allen Relationships

To appear at the International Journal on Very Large Databases (VLDBJ)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

C++ - used at university courses, my BSc thesis, my MSc thesis, PhD

Python – used at university courses, CERTH, PhD

Java (SE, EE) – used at university courses and various projects

C# – used at Natech S.A.

Database management – used at university courses, PhD

Machine learning techniques – used at multiple university courses, my BSc thesis, CERTH

Tensorflow, PyTorch – used at CERTH

ASP.NET MVC – used at Natech S.A.

OTHER SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Languages Greek (native), English (fluent), Dutch (fluent)

Interests Interval Data Indexing and retrieval, Spatial Data indexing and retrieval, Graph

Data, Machine Learning